Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
- II. Oral History Interviews
  - Fritz Reiche Interviews, 30 March 1962 - 9 May 1962; Reiche, F., (Fritz), 1883-1969
    - Session 1, 30 March 1962; 1 hour; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Reiche, F., (Fritz), 1883-1969; Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 6a)
    - Session 2, 4 April 1962; 2 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Reiche, F., (Fritz), 1883-1969; Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 8a)
    - Session 3, 9 May 1962; 2.25 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Reiche, F., (Fritz), 1883-1969 (Reel 11b, Reel 12a)
  - Leon Rosenfeld Interviews, 1 July 1963 - 22 July 1963; Heilbron, John L.; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Rosenfeld, L., (Leon), 1904-1974
    - Session 1, 1 July 1963; 2 hours (Reel 67a)
    - Session 2, 19 July 1963; 2 hours (Reel 67b)
    - Session 3, 22 July 1963; 2 hours (Reel 82b)
  - Adalbert Rubinowicz Interview, 18 May 1963; 2 hours; Heilbron, John L.; Kahan, Theo, b. 1904; Rubinowicz, Adalbert, (Wojciech), 1889-1974 (Reel 70a)
    Interview took place in Warsaw.
  - Ernest Rutherford Lecture, 1932; 0.5 hours; Rutherford, Ernest, 1871-1937 (Reel 29a)
    Lecture on nuclear physics given at Göttingen. Incomplete.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Recording provided by George Gamow.
  - Frau Erwin Schrödinger Interview, 5 April 1963; 1.25 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996 (Reel 60a)
    Interview took place in Vienna.
    Schrödinger, Erwin, 1887-1961
  - Betty Schultz Interview, 17 May 1963; 1.5 hours; Forman, Paul; Petersen, Aage; Schultz, Betty (Reel 85a)
  - Emilio Segrè Interview, 18 May 1964; 1.5 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Segrè, Emilio Gino, 1905-1989 (Reel 107a)
  - John C. Slater Interviews, 3 October 1963 - 8 October 1963; Slater, John C., (John Clarke), 1900-1976
    - Session 1, 3 October 1963; 2 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Slater, John C., (John Clarke), 1900-1976; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 89a, Reel 89b)
      Written transcript of interview available (530.1 Ar2.5), 41 pages.
    - Session 2, 8 October 1963; 2 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Slater, John C., (John Clarke), 1900-1976 (Reel 90a, Reel 90b)
  - Otto Stern Interviews, 29 May 1962 - 30 May 1963; Stern, Otto, 1888-1969
    - Session 1, 29 May 1962; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Stern, Otto, 1888-1969
    - Session 2, 30 May 1963; Hund, Friedrich, 1896-1997; Stern, Otto, 1888-1969
      Interview took place in Zurich. Unrecorded.
  - Otto Stuhlman Interview, 8 June 1962; 0.5 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Merzbacher, Eugen; Stuhlman, Otto, 1884-1965 (Reel 17a)
    Interview took place in Chapel Hill, North Carolina.
  - Geoffrey Ingram Taylor Interview, 9 May 1963; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Taylor, Geoffrey Ingram, Sir, 1886-1975
  - Hans Thirring Interview, 4 April 1963; 0.5 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Thirring, Hans, 1888-1976 (Reel 60a)
    Written transcript of interview available (530.1 Ar2.5), 5 pages.
  - L. H. Thomas Interview, 10 May 1962; 1.5 hours; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992; Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 12b)
  - G. P. Thomson Interview, 20 June 1963; 2 hours; Heilbron, John L.; Thomson, G. P., Sir, (George Paget), 1892-1975 (Reel 72b)
  - George Eugène Uhlenbeck Interviews, 30 March 1962 - 9 December 1963; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988
    - Sessions 1-2, 30 March 1962 - 31 March 1962; 1.5 hours (Reel 6b)
    - Session 3, 5 April 1962; 1.5 hours (Reel 8b)
    - Session 4, 10 May 1962; 0.5 hours (Reel 12b)
    - Session 5, 9 December 1963; 1.5 hours (Reel 96b)
  - Jean Ullmo Interview, 7 January 1963; 1 hour; Kahan, Theo, b. 1904; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Ullmo, Jean, 1906-1980 (Reel 42a)
  - Harold Clayton Urey Interviews, 24 March 1964; Heilbron, John L.; Urey, Harold Clayton, 1893-1981
    Interviews took place in La Jolla, California.
    - Session 1, 24 March 1964; 2 hours (Reel 102a)
    - Session 2, 24 March 1964; 0.5 hours (Reel 102b)
  - J. H. Van Vleck Interviews, 2 October 1963 - 4 October 1963; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980
    - Session 1, 2 October 1963; 2 hours (Reel 87b, Reel 87a)
    - Session 2, 4 October 1963; 2 hours (Reel 88b, Reel 88a)
  - Victor Frederick Weisskopf Interview, 10 July 1963; 2.5 hours; Heilbron, John L.; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1908-2002 (Reel 82a, Reel 81b)
  - Carl Friedrich von Weizsacker, 9 July 1963; 2 hours; Heilbron, John L.; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Weizsacker, Carl Friedrich, Freiherr von, 1912-2007 (Reel 81a)
  - Gregor Wentzel Interviews, 3 February 1964 - 5 February 1964; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Wentzel, Gregor, 1898-1978
    Three sessions took place in Chicago, Illinois. Unrecorded.
  - John Archibald Wheeler Interview, 24 March 1962; Heilbron, John L.; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Wheeler, John Archibald, 1911-2008
  - Eugene Paul Wigner Interviews, 21 November 1963 - 4 December 1963; Kuhn, Thomas S., 1922-1996; Wigner, Eugene Paul, 1902-1995
    - Session 1, 21 November 1963; 1.5 hours (Reel 92b)
    - Session 2, 3 December 1963; 2 hours (Reel 93a)
    - Session 3, 4 December 1963; 1.5 hours (Reel 93b)
  - Hideki Yukawa Interview, 10 July 1962; 0.75 hours; Wheeler, John Archibald, 1911-2008; Yukawa, Hideki, 1907-1981 (Reel 27a, Reel 27b)
    Interview took place in Kyoto, Japan.
- III. Sources for History of Quantum Physics Project
  Microfilm copies of the records of the project.
  Original records of the project: Mss.530.1.Ar2.5.
  - Biographies and Bibliographies, 2.0 Reel(s) (Reel 89-90)
    - Allison to Kramers, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel 89)
    - Kronig to Zwicky, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel 90)
  - Oral History Interview Transcripts, 5.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 1-5)
    - Allard to Dennison, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 1)
    - Dennison to Heisenberg, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 2)
    - Heisenberg to von Laue, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 3)
    - Lenard to Rubinowicz, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 4)
    - Rubinowicz to Zwicky, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel AHQP/OHI 5)
  - Inventory of Reels 1-72, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel 88)
  - Survey of European Libraries, Circa 1964; 1.0 Item(s) (Reel 58, Reel-frame 7)
    List of all libraries addressed and replies of those libraries reporting some material.
  - Various Universities, 1.0 Reel(s) (Reel 91)
    - Students
    - Faculty and Courses
- IV. Photographs, This is a selection of the photographs available from the Archive for the History of Quantum Physics.
  - Albert Einstein, 3/4 length, profile, informal with unidentified man., ca. 1950; 1.0 Photograph(s); Informal view of Einstein seated next to unidentified man.
  - Alfred Lande, 1956., 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 view, bust length portrait of Lande.
  - Born, Meitner, Heisenberg and Hahn, at the Lindau Conference of Nobel Laureates., 1962; 1.0 Photograph(s); Informal group photograph of Born, Meitner, Heisenberg and Hahn, standing outside.
  - Max Born, 1918., 1.0 Photograph(s); Bust length portrait of Max Born.
  - Department of Terrestrial Magnetism, April 21, 1935, Theoretical-Physics Conference sponsered by Carnegie Institution of Washington and Goerge Washington University at Washington, 1935, April 21; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of attendees of conference.
    An index of 39 names accompanies this photograph.
  - Enrico Fermi, Werner Heisenberg, Wofgang Pauli, Jr., half length, informal, seated., 1927, September; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait with hills and buildings in the background.
  - Fritz Reiche postcard., 1928; 1.0 Photograph(s); Postcard image of Reiche.
  - James Franck, 1961., 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of Franck.
  - Niels Bohr and A. Sommerfeld, half length, informal, standing., 1919; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait taken outside, exterior wall of building in background.
  - Klein, Franck, Bohr, Oseen and Born, 1922., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, taken outside.
  - Reiche, Polh, Ladenburg, Born and Hahn at St. Moritz, Switzerland, 1925., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of five men seated and six unidentified women standing.
  - Max and Marie Planck carte de visite., 1.0 Item(s); Group portrait of Max and Marie Planck.
  - Max Planck, ca. 1920., 1.0 Photograph(s); Profile of Planck.
  - Max Planck, formal portrait., 1925; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - Otto Lummer in lecture hall in Breslau on his 60th Birthday., 1920; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Lummer, lecturing in front of a seated crowd.
  - Paul Ehrenfest, J. M. Burgers and Father Burgers., ca. 1917; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length group portrait of Ehrenfest, Burgers and Burgers sitting at table.